Minibatch size is another hyper parameter
Minibatch 大小是另一个超参数
that no doubt you've run into a number of times already.
想必你已经遇到过很多次了
It has an effect on the resource requirements of the training
它对训练过程的资源要求有影响
process but also impacts training speed and number
但也会影响训练速度和
of iterations in a way that might not
迭代次数 而且这些影响
be as trivial as you may think.
不容小视
It's important to review a little bit of terminology
我们有必要先来了解一下
here first.
这个术语
Historically there had been debate on whether it's better
一直以来 人们都在争论哪种做法更好
to do online also called stochastic training
一种是在线随机训练
where you fit a single example of the dataset
你在单个训练步长中将数据集
to the model during a training step.
中的单个示例馈送给模型
And using only one example, do a forward pass,
然后仅用这一个示例进行前向传递
calculate the error, and then back propagate
计算误差 然后反向传播
and set adjusted values for all your parameters.
并设置所有参数的调整数值
And then do this again for each example in the dataset.
然后对数据集中的每个示例执行这个过程
Or if it was better to feed the entire dataset to the training
另一种是将整个数据集馈送给训练步长
step and calculate that gradient using
使用数据集中
the error generated by looking at all
所有示例的误差
the examples in the dataset.
来计算整个数据集的梯度
This is called batch training.
这叫做批量训练
The abstraction commonly used today
如今普遍使用的抽象
is to set a minibatch size.
是设置一个 minibatch 大小
So online training is when the minibatch size is one,
那么 在线训练的 minibatch 大小就为 1
and batch training is when the minibatch
而批量训练的 minibatch 大小
size is the same as the number of examples in the training
与训练集中的示例数量
set.
相同
And we can set the minibatch size
我们可以将 minibatch 大小设置为
to any value between these two values.
这两个值之间的任意值
The recommended starting values for your experimentation
当你进行试验时 建议初始值
are between one and a few hundred with 32
设在 1 到几百之间 32 通常
often being a good candidate.
是一个不错的选择
A larger minibatch size allows computational boosts
较大的 minibatch 大小会
that utilizes matrix multiplication, in the training
使训练计算中使用矩阵乘法的
calculations.
计算速度加快
But that comes at the expense of needing more memory
但这也会在训练过程中
for the training process, and generally,
占用更多的内存 总体来说
more computational resources.
需要更多的计算资源
Some out of memory errors and TensorFlow
如果遇到内存不足错误和 TensorFlow 问题
can be eliminated by decreasing the minibatch size.
可以通过减小 minibatch 大小来解决
It's important, however, to note that this computational boost
但是 需要注意的一点是计算速度增加
comes at a cost.
是有代价的
In practice, small minibatch sizes have more noise
在实践中 较小的 minibatch 大小会使误差计算
in their error calculations, and this noise
中有更多的噪声 而且此噪声
is often helpful in preventing the training process
通常有助于防止训练过程
from stopping at local minima on the error curve
在误差曲线上的局部最小值处停止
rather than the global minima that creates the best model.
而非创建最佳模型的全局最小值
So while the computational boost incentivizes
所以 虽然计算速度的提高会促使我们
us to increase the minibatch size,
增加 minibatch 大小
this practical algorithmic benefit
但实际的算法好处会使我们
incentivizes us to actually make it smaller.
选择将它变小
So in addition to 32, you might also
除了 32 之外 你还可以
want to try to experiment with 64 and 128 and 256.
使用 64、128 和 256 进行试验
And depending on your data and task,
根据你的数据和任务
you might have to experiment with other values as well.
你可能还需要尝试其他值
This is an experimental result for the effective batch size
这是卷积神经网络上有效批量的
on convolutional neural nets.
实验结果
It's from the paper titled Systematic evaluation of CNN
它来自一篇名为 “Systematic evaluation of CNN advances
advances on the image net.
on the ImageNet” 的文章
It shows that using the same learning
它显示在学习率相同的情况下
rate, the accuracy of the model decreases the larger
minibatch 大小越大
the minibatch size becomes.
模型的准确度越低
Now this is not only the effect of the minibike size,
这不仅在于 minibatch 大小的影响
but due to the fact that we need to change the learning rate
而且事实是当我们改变批量大小时
if we change the batch size.
我们还需要改变学习率
If we do adjust the learning rate as we increase the batch
如果我们在增加批量大小的同时
size, we can see that the accuracy does decrease,
调整学习率 可以看到准确度会随批量大小
but only slightly, the more increase the batch size.
增加而下降 不过只是轻微的下降
So to sum up for the minibatch size,
所以总结来说 如果 minibatch 大小
too small could be too slow, too large could be computationally
太小 会使训练速度很慢 太大会导致
taxing and could result in worse accuracy, and 32 to 256
计算成本过高 并降低准确度 所以 32 至 256
are potentially good starting values for you
是你进行试验的
to experiment with.
不错的初始值选择